(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-18T01:19:04.373877",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
いくよ、開拓者
Here we go, pioneers!
あの日選んで決めた道は
The path I chose and decided on that day
間違いだったんだろうって過去を恨んでみても
Even if I regret the past, wondering if it was a mistake,
どうしゃぶりの雨が責め立てて
A sudden downpour pelts down mercilessly,
俯いた顔は酷く弱いことに気付いた
Realizing how dreadfully weak my downcast face was.
この先には叶えたいことや夢があるから
Because there are dreams and things I want to fulfill ahead,
目を逸らさないように
So I won't look away.
正解はない 誰だってひとりで
There is no right answer, everyone is alone,
想うまま始まっていく この物語
This story begins just as we feel.
今をただ走って 季節を駆け巡って
Just running through the present, traversing the seasons,
見えない闇の中で
Within the unseen darkness.
痛みだってあるよ 戸惑いだってあるよ
There is pain, there is bewilderment,
それでもここで生きていくと 決めたんだ 決めたから 前を向いて
Even so, I decided to live right here, so facing forward...
生き方を誰かに決められて 本当はそうじゃなかったとか今さら嘆いたって
Lamenting now that my path was chosen by someone else, and that wasn't really true
味方も英雄（ヒーロー）も現れなくて 喧騒の中でどこか彷徨り果てていた
With no allies or heroes appearing, I wandered and exhausted myself in the clamor.
この先には奏でたい音や歌があるから 耳を澄まし澄ますように
Because there are songs I want to play ahead, I will keep straining my ears to listen.
間違いはない 誰だってひとりで
There's no mistake, everyone is alone,
綴り綴られていく この物語
This story continues to be spelled out.
過去、今、未来があなたを駆け巡って
Past, present, and future run all around you,
理想と現実の中で
Amidst ideals and reality.
泣きたくなるよ 諦めたくなるよ
It makes me want to cry, it makes me want to give up,
それでもここで生きていくと 決めたんだ 決めたから
Even so, I decided to live right here, because I decided to...
走り出すよ
Let's start running!
生まれ変わってもこの話をしよう
Even if I'm reborn, let's tell this story.
この人生でよかったと
Glad to have lived this life,
痛みは力に 戸惑いは期待に
turning pain into strength, hesitation into hope,
そうしてここで生きていくそう
and living right here, yes.
今をただ走って 季節を駆け巡って
Running through the present, racing seasons,
見えない不安の中で
amidst unseen anxiety,
痛みだってあるよ 戸惑いだってあるよ
There is pain, there is hesitation,
それでもここで生きていくそう
and yet, I will live right here.
決めたんだ
I've decided!
AZKi! 右手にマイク、左手に地図
AZKi! Mic in the right hand, map in the left,
あなたのハートをゼロゲスさ！
zero-guessing your heart!
ということでAZKiでーす！
With that said, I'm AZKi!
えー今日はAZKi 5thバースデーライブ「DESTINATION」に
Thank you so much for coming to AZKi's 5th
お越しいただきありがとうございます！
Birthday Live 'DESTINATION'!
え、早いもので、5回目の誕生日を迎えます。
Time flies, and I'm celebrating my 5th birthday.
え、今日お祝いしに来てくれたみんな、
Everyone who came to celebrate today,
ありがとーーー！
thank you so much!
ありがとう、たくさんのお祝いありがとうございます。
Thank you for all the celebrations.
え、今日のですね、ハッシュタグは、#AZKi生誕ライブ2023でございます。
Today's hashtag is #AZKi生誕ライブ2023.
たくさんスクショ&ツイートよろしくお願いいたします！
Please take plenty of screenshots and tweets!
さて、今回のライブタイトル「DESTINATION」なんですけれども、
As for today's live title, 'DESTINATION',
AZKiが命名いたしました。
I named it myself.
このタイトルに込めた意味を、今日のこのライブを通して、
I hope I can convey the meaning behind it
みんなに伝えることができたらいいなと思っています。
to everyone through today's live.
「DESTINATION」つまり、目的地とは、どこ、なのかな？
'DESTINATION', in other words, where or what is the destination?
AZKiはどこへ向かっていくのか、目的地をゲストできるのか、
Where is AZKi heading? Can you guess the destination?
という最後まで目を離さないでくださいね！はい！
Please keep your eyes on it till the very end!
ということで、1曲目は「小さな心が決めたこと」ということで、
The first song is 'Chiisana Kokoro ga Kimeta Koto',
私が初めて作詞作曲させていただいた曲です。
the first song I ever wrote lyrics and music for.
今日のこのサブタイトルにも繋がって、
Connecting to today's subtitle,
活動を始めたときの気持ちだったり、こうやって音楽を届けたいという気持ちを忘れないように今日1曲目に歌わせていただきました。
I sang it as the first song today to never forget my initial feelings and desire to deliver music.
そして本日は最後には何やら重大発表、
There will be a major announcement at the end,
そしてメンバー限定でアンコールライブもございますので、ぜひぜひお見逃しなく！
and an exclusive encore live for members, so please don't miss it!
ということで今日は本当にもりだくさんなので、どんどん歌っていきたいと思います！
Today is really packed, so I want to keep singing!
それでは次の曲に行きたいと思います。聞いてください。「without U」！
Well then, let's move on to the next song. Please listen to 'without U'!
君がいるから ひとりじゃないから
Because you are here, because I'm not alone,
ずうっとひとりだけで 同じ言葉ばかり
Always all by myself, just repeating words,
なんか寂しくなっちゃうよね
it somehow gets kind of lonely, right?
キミがいるから 一人じゃないから
Because you're here, because I'm not alone,
ずっと 一人だけで 同じことばかり
I've always been all alone, repeating the same things,
何か 寂しくなっちゃうよね
and it gets kind of lonely, doesn't it?
俯いてばかりで 明日もわからない
Always looking down, not even knowing tomorrow.
こんな 足りないものみたいに
Like something lacking like this,
はじめからおしまいまで きっと小さなわたし
from start to finish, I'm surely just small me.
“A→Z”“K→i”
"A→Z", "K→i"
…世界に怯えている
...cowering in this world.
だから
That's why...
without U――キミがいないときっと
without U—If you weren't here,
私は私でいられないんだ
I surely couldn't be myself.
I need U――私を見て、聞いて！
I need U—Look at me, listen to me!
そうしたらきっと届けられるから
If you do, I'm sure I can reach you.
キミがいるって 一人じゃないって
Saying you're here, that I'm not alone,
歩き通しなのは 私だけじゃなくて
I wasn't the only one walking all this way.
きっと こうしているときでも
I'm sure even at times like this,
キミは ずっとずっと 頑張っていたんだね
you kept working so hard all this time.
私は全部見ているから
Because I see all of it.
つま先からてっぺんまで 小さな心ぜんぶ
From my toes to the top of my head, my whole small heart,
“Z→A”“i→K”
"Z→A", "i→K"
…伝える想いがここに
...the feelings I want to convey are right here.
それは
That is...
beside U――キミのそばにいるよ
beside U—I'll be by your side,
どんなに 辛く思ったときでも
no matter how painful it felt.
I read U――聞かせて、キミの声！
I read U—Let me hear your voice!
そこに私の 声を重ねたら
When I layer my voice over yours,
傍にいる――
I'm right by your side—
もらったものを 抱え通し返し足りないくらいだよ
Holding all that you've given me, it's almost not enough to return.
一人じゃない わかったものね
I realized I'm not alone.
いつまでこうしていられるの?
How long can we stay like this?
そんなこと わからないよ
I don't know things like that.
わからないから 歌うんだよ!
That's why I sing, because I don't know!
キミといる この瞬間 大切なものにするために――!
To make this moment with you precious—!
そうだ
That's right.
without U――キミがいないときっと 私は私でいられなかった
without U—If you weren't here, I surely couldn't be myself.
I need U――私を見て、聞いて! そうしたらきっと きっと これからも...
I need U—Look at me, listen! If you do, surely, forever from now...
だから
Therefore,
within U――キミのなかにいるよ キミがくれたものの その限りに
within U—I'm inside you, to the very limit of what you gave me.
I with U――どうか、覚えていて! 私がここに立つ ときはいつも
I with U—Please remember! Whenever I stand here,
キミがいるから 一人じゃないから
because you're here, because I'm not alone.
beside U――キミのそばにいるよ
beside U—I'll be by your side,
どんなに 辛く思ったときでも
no matter how painful it felt.
私たちは私っていられないのかな また
Could we still be ourselves? Again...
I read U――私を見て聞いて
I read U—Look at me and listen,
そうしたらきっと きっとこれからも...
if you do, surely, forever from now...
きっと
surely,
だから
That's why
within U――キミのなかにいるよ キミがくれたものの
within U—I'm inside you, within what you gave me,
その限りに
to the absolute limit.
I with U――どうか、覚えていて! 私がここに立つ ときはいつも
I with U—Please remember! Whenever I stand here,
キミがいるから 一人じゃないから
because you're here, because I'm not alone.
Because you're here, because I'm not alone,
一人じゃないから
because I'm not alone.
愛が言葉を見失っている
Love is losing its words.
空が涙を降らせていたんだ
The sky was letting fall its tears.
誰の為に 何の為に
For whose sake? For what purpose?
これが運命だと言うの？
Is this what you call fate?
嘘が街を包み込んでいる
Lies are enveloping the city.
鳥が飛べずに声を上げていた
Birds were unable to fly, raising their voices.
たった一つの存在を灯す
Lighting a single existence,
この場所でキミを待っている
I'm waiting for you right here in this place.
世界はとても苦しそうでした
The world seemed to be in so much pain.
歌うことが正しいかなんて
Whether singing is the right thing
今も答えは見つからないけど
I still can't find the answer,
確かなのは君がいたから
but what I know for sure is you were there,
私はここにいるの
so I am here right now.
何回何十回だって
No matter how many tens of times,
君と出会うから
I'll meet you again.
夜が明けていく光が降り注ぎ
As the night breaks and light pours down,
喜び悲しみを重ね微笑む
weaving joy and sorrow, I smile.
君と生きるこの場所で
Living with you in this place,
それが私の世界だ
that is my world.
その一秒一瞬が煌めく yeah
Every single second sparkles, yeah.
過去を道を壊したとしても
Even if I break the path of the past,
夢が街を食らい尽くそうとしても
Even if dreams try to devour the town,
大丈夫だから側にいるよ
It's alright, I'm right by your side.
君に笑っていてほしいんだ
I want to see you smile.
生まれた意味を探しているの
Searching for the meaning of being born,
転んでもただ走り続けていく
Stumbling, yet continuing to run onward,
今を知って明日を投げた
Knowing the present, throwing away tomorrow,
心が叫びたがってる
My heart is yearning to cry out.
タイムマシンに乗ってさ
If I could ride a time machine
別の未来を選ぶことができたなら
and choose a different future,
君のいない世界も想像する そんな世界は想像できない
Imagining a world without you... such a world is unimaginable.
何回何十回だって
No matter how many tens of times,
君を選ぶから
I will choose you.
夜が滲んでいく地平線の彼方へ
Toward the horizon where the night bleeds,
途切る呼吸の音を
I felt the sound of our intermittent
確かに感じた
breath for sure.
始めよう君との未来を
Let's begin our future together,
辛い夜手を取って離さないで
Without letting go of painful nights.
大きな声で名前を呼んで
Calling out your name in a loud voice,
奇跡を駆け抜けてどこまででも行けるよ
I can run through miracles and go anywhere.
ここからもう一度君と私で始めよう
Let's start over once more, you and I.
無限の中に生まれる物語を
Walking with you through the story
君と歩いていく
born in infinity.
この世界が悲しみに溢れていたとしても
Even if this world overflows with sadness,
私は歌を歌い続けていく
I will keep on singing songs.
君と生きるこの場所でそれが私の世界だ
Living with you in this place, that is my world.
その一秒一瞬が煌めく yeah
Every single second sparkles, yeah.
傷つき涙を流す君が
May the world become one where
幸せだと思える世界になりますように
you can feel happy, even through tears.
願いを込め歌う
Singing with a wish in my heart.
画面の中の君が好き
I love you inside the screen.
君を初めて見つけた時
When I first found you,
なぜか心揺さぶられたんだ
For some reason, my heart was shaken.
つくりものに命を宿す
Breathing life into something artificial,
君の輝きは本物だった
Your radiance was real.
楽しそうな君は素敵だった
You looked so happy, and it was wonderful.
画面の中の君が好き
I love you inside the screen.
ただ君が笑えたらいい 本当の君とは実は違うとしても
If only you could smile, even if the real you is actually different.
新しい扉を開けて 息をしようよ
Let's open a new door and take a breath together.
嘘も本当も関係ないから
Because lies and truth don't matter.
息をしている瞬間を僕ら
The moments we spend breathing...
ほどけたいんだ 君が好きだから
I want to unravel, because I love you.
君を初めて見つけた時 なぜか心揺さぶられたんだ
When I first found you, my heart was somehow shaken.
創り物にいのちを宿す
Breathing life into a creation,
君の輝きは本物だった
your radiance was real.
楽しそうな君は素敵だった
You looked so happy, and it was wonderful.
もしも君が生きづらいなら
If life is hard for you,
好きな顔と服を着てもいい
it's okay to wear your favorite face and clothes.
もしも君が辞めたくなっても
Even if you want to quit,
僕らは止めたりしないからさ
we won't try to stop you.
生きやすい場所を探せばいい
You just need to find a place where you can live easily.
君の言葉が、僕に刺さった。
Your words pierced through me.
君の歌に、僕は揺さぶられた。
Your song shook my soul.
君の配信に、僕は夢中になった。
I became obsessed with your streams.
画面の中の君が、僕を救ってくれた。
You inside the screen saved me.
いつか画面の外へいなくなっても
Even if you eventually disappear from outside the screen,
画面の中にいた君のことを
the you who lived inside the screen—
君自身が生きてくれてたら 嬉しいな
if you yourself are living on, I'd be so happy.
ただ君が笑えたらいい
As long as you can smile,
本当の君と実は違うとしても
even if it differs from the real you,
新しい扉を開けて 息をしようよ
opening a new door, let's take a breath.
君の奇跡は嘘も 本当も抱きしめるよ
Your miracle will embrace both lies and truth.
君にとってこの場所が生きる糧になれたなら
If this place could become your sustenance for living,
僕らは幸せだ
we would be happy.
幸せだから
Because we are happy.
みんなも一緒に歌ってね！
Everyone sing along with me!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
画面の中の君が好き
[Title: Gamen no Naka no Kimi ga Suki]
ということで、お聴きいただいたのは Without You、インディーズワールド、画面の中の君が好きでした！
With that, the songs you just heard were 'Without You,' 'Indies World,' and 'Gamen no Naka no Kimi ga Suki'!
いかがでしたでしょうか？
How was it, I wonder?
えー、これまでのね、AZKiにとって欠かせない楽曲を選んで歌わせていただきました。
Um, I chose and sang songs that are indispensable to AZKi up until now.
そう、最近AZKiを知ってくれたという方もきっと多いと思います。
That's right, I'm sure many of you have gotten to know AZKi recently.
初めてライブ見るよっていう人……おう？
People who are watching my live for the first time... oh?
お、お、いますね、いますね、いますね！いやーー、嬉しい！
Oh, oh, there are, there are, there are! Man, I'm so happy!
こうやってライブをみんなで見に来てくれる日が本当に、本当に本当に嬉しいです。
I'm truly, truly, truly happy that the day has come when everyone comes to see my live like this.
え、AZKi今年はね、本当に大きな転機があった年だなと思っていまして、え、チーズのお姉さんと言われるようになったきっかけの年でもあったし
Um, AZKi, this year really felt like a huge turning point for me, and it was also the year I came to be called the 'cheese older sister'...
え、今までのでこうずっと、まあ歌をね中心に活動してきたんですけれども、その歌とは違う側面からみんなにも知ってもらえたり、楽しんでもらえたりする機会があったのはすごく大きかったです。
Um, up until now I've been active mainly focusing on singing, but it was huge to have opportunities for everyone to know and enjoy me from a different aspect than just singing.
え、なんでちょっと改めてね、なんかこう「AZKiってどんな、どんな活動してきたの？」みたいなところからの話になるんですけど
Um, so revisiting that, it leads to talking about 'What kind of activities has AZKi done?' and such.
えーっと、本当に、うんと、これまで決してこう平坦な道ではありませんでした。
Um, truly, um, up until now it has by no means been a smooth path.
え、今まではですね、えっと、ホロライブ所属で活動させてもらっていますが
Um, up until now, um, I've been active belonging to Hololive,
え、活動始めたときはですね、イノナカミュージックという音楽レーベルで活動を始めました。
um, when I started my activities, I started in a music label called INNK Music.
え、そして、え、AZKiは実わ2022年の7月に活動終了予定だったんですけれども
And, um, AZKi actually had activities scheduled to end in July 2022, but
え、その活動終了予定であった、え、ルートアルファから、そのそこを終わらないで終わりの向こうを目指す、ルートベータというね、えっと、道の分岐があったんですよ。そうなんです。
um, from Route Alpha, which was scheduled to end activities, there was a branching of the road called Route Beta, aiming beyond the end without stopping there. That's right.
はい、そして、ま自分の中でもすごく大きかったのが、イノナカミュージックの若いさんということで
Yes, and, well, what was huge for me within myself was Wakai-san from INNK Music, and so on...
このタイミングで
At this timing...
えっと、卒業も考えていました。
Um, I was also considering graduation.
でも今こうやってライブができて、
But now, being able to hold a live concert like this,
AZKiがこうやって存在しているのは、そのAZKiを続けようと決めた私自身でもあり、
and AZKi existing here like this is partly myself deciding to keep going,
ま、その思いをね、受け入れてくれたホロライブやカバーの皆さんのおかげで、
and thanks to everyone at Hololive and Cover who accepted those feelings,
がいて、
being there...
ま、その本当にそういうことを決めようと思った
and the one who really gave me that huge, massive push
大きな、大きな、その背中を押してくれたっていうのは本当に開拓者の皆さんがいたからです。
when I decided to do that, was truly because all of you, the pioneers, were there.
一番こう辛いときに頑張っていた過去の私にも感謝したいし、
I want to thank my past self who worked hard during the hardest times,
昔からね、応援してくれてる開拓者のみんなにも感謝したいです。
and I also want to thank all the pioneers who have cheered me on since long ago.
そして、今今日こうやって応援してくれるみんながいるから、今日、この今のAZKiがあります。本当にありがとう。
And because everyone is here cheering me on today, today's AZKi exists. Thank you so much.
2023年、今日からね、そう、ちょうど折り返し地点ですね。
2023, starting today... yes, we're right at the halfway point.
またこれからどんなことが起こるのか、どんなことができるのか、ぜひ楽しみにしていて欲しいです。
I hope you'll look forward to seeing what kind of things will happen and what we can do from here on out.
はい。ね、それでは、ちょっとしみじみとしたところで、しみじみとしたところで、次の曲に行きたいなと思います。
Yes. Well then, keeping it a bit sentimental, I'd like to move on to the next song.
ま、AZKiの本当に、この、ま、今日は目的地っていうタイトルになってるんですけど、まあ、そういう目的地に行くときにはいろんな分岐点があって、そのAZKiの分岐点には本当にたくさんの人がいて、大切な人がたくさんいます。
Well, AZKi's, truly, this... well, today's title is "Destination," but when heading to such a destination, there are various branching paths, and at AZKi's branching paths there are truly many people, and many precious people.
そんなね、大切な人に届けたい歌を、歌いたいと思います。
I'd like to sing a song I want to deliver to such precious people.
それでは
So then,
聞いてください。
please listen.
大切なお知らせ
[Title: Important Notice]
今まで私と一緒にいてくれて本当にありがとう
Thank you so much for being with me until now.
もうすぐお別れだね
It's almost time to say goodbye.
二人で刻んだ詩をなぞって
Let's trace the poetry we carved together,
ずっといつものくだらない話はしようよ
and always talk about our usual silly things.
そっと抱きしめて
Hold me close gently.
今まで本当に色々あったね始発で旅したり誕生日を忘れたり
Up until now, we've really been through a lot—taking trips on the first train, forgetting birthdays,
ディナーの目覚ましでヒヤヒヤしたり
or getting cold sweats from dinner alarms.
全部全部が宝物だから全部全部が
Everything, absolutely everything is a treasure, so everything, everything...
宝物なんだから
because they are treasures,
全部全部があなたと繋がってるから
because everything, absolutely everything is connected to you.
夢で会えたらまた話そうね
If we can meet in a dream, let's talk again.
水も甘いもあなたから教わった心の熱さは冷めることなくずっとずっと
You taught me both the sweet and bitter, and the warmth in my heart will never cool down, forever and ever,
ともに続けて恋し続けて今あなたのこと愛してる
continuing together, continuing to love you, right now I love you.
今まで私と一緒にいてくれて本当にありがとう
Thank you so much for being with me until now.
いつも言ってるけど知らない世界を教えてくれた
Even though I always say it, you taught me a world I didn't know.
全部全部が新しい景色で全部全部にあなたが残っているよ
Everything is a new scenery, and you remain in every single thing.
いつか必ず会いに行くからあなたと過ごして木漏れ日はなかったよ
Someday I will surely go meet you, and spending time with you...
心の熱さは冷めることなくずっとずっと共に続けて
The warmth in my heart will never cool down, continuing together forever and ever,
恋し続けて今あなたのこと愛してる
continuing to love you, right now I love you.
春色もよの空見上げて過ぎ行く時間を委ねた
Looking up at the spring-colored sky, I surrendered to the passing time.
思い出は尽きることなく
Memories will never run out...
もう少しだけ もう少しだけ
Mou sukoshi dake, mou sukoshi dake
踏み出せたのなら
If I could take just one more step forward,
そう小さな優しさを取り分け合えたのなら
letting us share such a little kindness...
ありふれた一日が素敵な日になっていくほら
Even an ordinary day will turn into something wonderful.
夢で会えたら また話そうね
If I could meet you in a dream, let's talk again.
甘いも甘いもあなたから教わった
Sweet, or maybe a bit bitter, I learned it from you.
好きなところも 嫌いなところも
Favorite places, and places I hate, too.
向き合い続けて気付けば驚った
Facing them, if I realized it, I was surprised.
世界で一番優しい人よ
Hey, you're the kindest person in the world!
世界で一番不器用な人よ
Hey, you're the clumsiest person in the world!
どうしようもなく好きなんだずっと ずっと
I love you so much, always, always.
恋し続けて 愛し続けて
Loving you, continuing to love you...
もう大嫌いって 大好きだよ
I hate you so much, but I love you so much.
息をしている だから生きている
I'm breathing, so I'm alive.
当然のことを誰も疑わないの
Nobody doubts the obvious.
息をしているように見えている
It looks like I'm breathing.
青が染め出す 私にとっての何か
Blue bleeds into something just for me.
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat is pounding away.
叩かれても腐らずに
Even if I'm rejected, I won't rot away.
此処で歌うよ
I'll sing right here.
ボタン一つのいのち
A single life with a single button.
最後まで私のこと覚えててくれるの
Will you remember me until the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの
It feels like I'm going to fade away.
わかってよ わかってよ ねぇ
Understand me, please, hey.
本当ってどうなの 恋とは何処なんでしょう
What is love really like?
君が忘れちゃったら私はいなくなるの
If you forget, I'll cease to exist.
命のような夢を見てるよ
Watching a dream like life.
またね、バイバイ。
See you later, bye-bye.
息をしている だから生きている
I'm breathing, so I'm alive.
自己証明を欲しがって欲しがっているんだ
I want to prove myself, I want to.
音が止まって 動かなくなって
The sound stops and everything freezes.
そんな私を君は笑ってくれるかな
Can you smile at a pathetic me like this?
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat is pounding away.
嫌われても腐らずに
Even if I'm hated, I won't rot away.
此処で歌うよ 気分次第のいのち
I'll sing right here, whenever I feel like it.
最後まで私のこと見届けてくれるの
Will you remember me until the very end?
覚めてしまいそうなの
It feels like I'm going to wake up.
わかってよ わかってよ ねぇ
Understand me, please, hey.
しょっぱい涙が出ちゃう穿孔
Salty tears are spilling over.
君が忘れちゃったら私はいなくなるの
If you forget, I'll cease to exist.
命のような夢を見てるよ
Watching a dream like life.
またね、バイバイ。
See you later, bye-bye.
ふきこんだあの 日を 軽くいじらないで やめて
Don't lightly meddle with those memories, stop it.
それが生きる糧になるから
Because that's what keeps me alive.
大丈夫 ずっと私は歌い続けるから
It's okay, I will always keep singing.
息をしている 君は生きている
You are breathing, you are alive.
当然のこと 誰も疑わないの
It's natural, no one doubts it.
息をしている ように見えている
It looks as if you are breathing.
生の裏側 私にとっての 何か
What is the flip side of life to me?
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat is pounding away.
叩かれても 腐らずに 此処で歌うよ
Even if struck, without rotting, I'll sing here.
ボタン一つの いのち
A life of a single button.
最後まで 私のこと 覚えててくれるの？
Will you remember me until the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの わかってよ わかってよねえ
I feel like I'm going to fade—please understand!
本当のとこどうなの？ 恋と推しは違うんです？
How is it really? Are love and an oshi different?
君が忘れちゃったら 私は居なくなるの
If you forget me, I will cease to exist.
命のような夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life itself.
またね バイバイ
See you later, bye-bye.
息をしている だから生きている
I'm breathing, therefore I'm alive.
自己証明を 欲しがっているんだ
Craving proof of my own existence.
音が止まって 動かなくなって
When the sound stops and I can no longer move,
そんな私を 君は笑ってくれるかな？
will you smile at such a me?
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat is pounding away.
嫌われても 腐らずに 此処で歌うよ
Even if hated, without rotting, I'll sing here.
気分次第の いのち
A life depending on my mood.
最後まで 私のこと 見届けてくれるの？
Will you watch over me until the very end?
覚めてしまいそうなの わかってよ わかってよねえ
I feel like I'm waking up—please understand!
声が聴こえるんだよ
I can hear a voice,
塩辛い涙が出ちゃうほど
enough to bring salty tears.
君が忘れちゃったら 私は居なくなるの
If you forget me, I will cease to exist.
命のような夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life itself.
またね バイバイ
See you later, bye-bye.
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ 呼び合う声を合図に
Parade, parade, parade! Shining bright, using our calling voices as a signal!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 探しに行くよ スタートは何度だって
Parade, parade, parade! How many times have we started searching?
Parade, Parade, Parade!
探しに行くよ
Going out to search,
スタートは何度だって
the start is however many times it takes.
ざらついたゲストを連れて来ちゃいました！
We brought a rough guest along!
Our Bright Parade! また明日ねおめでとう！
Our Bright Parade! See you tomorrow, congratulations!
これからも空の下で物語を始めよう
From now on too, let's start our story under the open sky.
ただ独り言をつぶった
I had simply muttered to myself.
ただ始まりたくて走った
I had simply run because I wanted to begin.
遠く暗がりに灯った
A light flickered in the distant gloom.
それは眩しすぎた名前 それは優しすぎる思い出
That was a name too dazzling, that was a memory too gentle.
近づけと手を伸ばした 想いがけず結び合った
I reached out my hand to get closer, and unexpectedly our feelings bound together.
ほら 今 迷子は “僕等” になった
Look, now the lost ones have become "us".
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! Shining bright,
悔しさも愛しさも連れておいで
bring along both frustration and affection!
風、夢、羽 飛び立てばいいさ
Wind, dreams, feathers—just take flight!
ささやかな祈りは光 終わりなき兆し 君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
A modest prayer is light, a never-ending omen—finding you makes me proud.
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
まだ頼りない予感も 歌おう恥ずかしかなんてないよ
Let's sing even of still-uncertain premonitions—there's nothing to be shy about.
誰も解けないイマジネーション いつかまた逢えるおまじない
An imagination no one can solve, a spell so we can meet again someday.
あの日ゼロに始まったストーリー 数え切れない言の葉
A story that began at zero that day, countless words.
数えるような想いじゃないさ ほら 今 “僕等” を一つと呼ぼう
Not feelings you can simply count—look, now let's call "us" one.
Parade, Parade, Parade! 美しいんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's so beautiful,
許し合える刹那 夜はきらめく
a fleeting moment where we forgive each other, the night sparkles.
雨、晴れ、カレイド またとない空 相応しい旅路とは
Rain, shine, kaleidoscope—a sky like no other, what is a fitting journey?
君と在ること
It is being with you.
叩いた今を 聞けば おかえりって叫ぶよ
When I listen to the present we've tapped, I shout "Welcome home!"
当たり前じゃないか... Parade, Parade, Parade!
Isn't it only natural? ... Parade, parade, parade!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining!
呼び合う声を合図に
With the voices calling out as our signal,
君だ 僕だ！
it's you, it's me!
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining!
悔しさも愛しさも連れて
Bringing along both frustration and love,
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
wind, dreams, and wings will let us take flight!
ささやかな祈りは光
Our quiet prayers become the light,
終わりなき兆し
an endless sign of hope.
君と飛び込んでいく素敵なスタートさ
Diving in with you is such a wonderful start!
ここから これから Our Bright Parade!
From here, from now on, our bright parade!
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
*(Instrumental Music)*
なんと！サプライズゲストにそらちゃんが来てくれました！
And lo and behold! Sora-chan came as a surprise guest!
イェーイ！お誕生日おめでとう！
Yay! Happy birthday!
ありがとう！嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm so happy!
活動し始めてから、そらちゃんとは本当に一番
Ever since I started activities, Sora-chan and I have truly been...
AZKiと活動形態が近かったこともあって
Our activity styles were close,
本当に苦しい時も楽しい時も相談したりとか、いろいろ連絡取ったりとかしてて
and through truly painful times and fun times, we'd consult each other and keep in touch.
本当に戦友でもあり、親友でもあり
Truly comrades-in-arms and best friends alike.
Our Bright Paradeを歌いながら、いろいろあったもんね
Singing "Our Bright Parade" together, we've been through a lot, haven't we?
活動始めた頃から仲良くしてもらっていました
We've been close since around when we started our activities.
だから今こうやって一緒に歌えることにとっても感謝しています
So I'm very grateful to be able to sing together like this now.
いやいや、こちらこそ！一緒に歌えて本当に嬉しい、ありがとうね
No, no, the feeling's mutual! I'm so happy to sing together, thank you!
本当にね、AZKi辛い時とか、くじけそうな時
Truly, AZKi, when times were tough or I felt like giving up,
そらちゃんが前にいると思って、そらちゃんの頑張ってる姿とか、いろんな活動してるの、その背中を見て頑張ってこれました
thinking Sora-chan was ahead of me, seeing you work hard and do various activities, looking at your back helped me keep going.
だから今日は一緒にこのAZKiの誕生日に来てくれて、歌ってくれて本当にありがとうございます
So thank you so much for coming together on AZKi's birthday and singing with me today.
私もいつもAZKiちゃんと一緒に歩いてこれたから、ここまで頑張ってこれたと思うので
I think I've been able to work hard up to now because I always walked together with AZKi-chan,
お祝いに来れてとっても嬉しいです
so I'm very happy to come celebrate.
そんなそらずなんですけれども、なんと今日、最速で披露したくて2人の曲を作ってきました！
With that said, we actually made a song for the two of us because we wanted to debut it at the fastest possible time today!
今日はみんなにいち早く聞いてほしいんですけど、リリースは計画中ということで
We want everyone to hear it as soon as possible today, but its release is currently in planning,
計画中だってよ！後日発表します！
it's in planning! We'll announce it at a later date!
それでは聴いてください。「Scale the walls」！
So please listen to it: "Scale the walls"!
*(Instrumental Music)*
吸った向こう側の気配 きっと目に映そう
The presence on the other side of what we inhaled will surely reflect in our eyes.
*(Instrumental Music)*
誤魔化さず言って 言葉積み重ねよう
Let's speak without masking and pile up our words.
高すぎる壁さえも跳んでしまうから
Because we'll leap over even walls that are too high,
通り抜けたって何にも楽しくないって
that just passing right through them isn't fun at all—
Never enough 君が教えてくれていたんだ
Never enough, you had taught me that.
Ah 夢を散々掛け合わせ
Ah, multiplying our dreams over and over,
時に so so 間違って
sometimes making so-so mistakes,
それも laugh laugh 気にせずに 何度でも挑もう だって I know myself
without worrying about laugh-laugh either, let's challenge ourselves any number of times, because I know myself!
意味のない評価で世界比べないで
Don't compare the world with meaningless evaluations;
叶えたい本音はすべてを包み込む太陽
the true feelings we want to fulfill are a sun that embraces everything.
いっそ好き放題上を目指して 立ちはだかる壁を登って
All the more, aiming high as we please, climbing the towering walls,
刻んでいきたいな そして次に臨む越えたいあの未来
I want to carve them into existence, and then face and surpass that future we wish for next!
*(Instrumental Music)*
想像したら 鼓動が聞こえたんだ
When I imagined it, I heard my heartbeat.
作り込んだ道なんて 全部従わず行こう
Let's not follow any fabricated paths.
響く音のまま 心が赴くまま
Just as the sound echoes, just as the heart desires,
ずっと 君なら 君なら 一緒に なんでも 気づける
always—if it's with you, together we can realize anything.
躓いて 視界が 何も見えなくなっても
Even if I stumble and my vision goes dark,
振り向いて 笑える そんな場所がある
there is a place where I can turn back and smile.
ただ 楽しもう
Let's just have fun.
夢を散々 掛け合わせ 時にSo so 間違って
Multiplying dreams like crazy, sometimes making mistakes, so so,
それもLaugh laugh 気にせずに 何度でも挑もう
but laughing it off, laugh laugh, without caring, let's challenge it over and over.
いつもBe yourself 試さないと ほら 何も始まらない
Always be yourself. If you don't try, you see, nothing begins.
些細な勇気で 明日を変えるまで もっと
With a tiny bit of courage, until we change tomorrow, even more—
意味のない評価で 世界比べないで
Don't compare yourself to the world with meaningless evaluations.
叶えたい本音は すべてを包み込む 太陽
Our true feelings we want to fulfill are a sun that embraces everything.
いっそ 好き放題 上を目指して 立ちはだかる壁を 登って
Rather, aiming for the top as we please, climbing the walls standing in our way,
刻んでいきたいな
I want to etch it into existence.
そして次に臨む 超えたいあの未来
And next, facing that future we want to surpass,
抱こう 壮大な未来
let's embrace a grand future!
ここまでの 1,690日。
1,690 days up to this point.
始めの頃の私が歩いていた道は、いつも道標があって、
The path I walked in the beginning always had signposts,
分からないところでもちゃんと歩けてた。
and even where I didn't understand, I was able to walk properly.
雨の日も、風の日も、寒い日も、暑い日も、
Rain or shine, wind or storm, cold days or hot days—
最初の地図に描かれた通りに歩いた。
I walked exactly as drawn on the initial map.
2枚目に渡された地図。
The map handed to me as the second one
真っ白だった。
was completely blank.
いつも矢印の方向に進んでたから、何にも分からなくなった。
Because I had always followed the arrows, I didn't understand anything anymore.
頭も真っ白になったし、初めて「孤独」や「不安」を覚えた。
My mind went blank too, and for the first time, I felt loneliness and anxiety.
世界が怖かった。
The world was terrifying.
それでも私なりに考えて、考えて、考えて、初めて地図を作ることにした。
Even so, thinking, thinking, and thinking in my own way, I decided to make a map for the first time.
きっとスローペースだったけど、
It was surely at a slow pace, but
描いているうちに何だか景色が色々見える様になった。
as I drew it, somehow various sceneries began to come into view.
最初の地図に描かれていたゴールも飛び越えて、
Vaulting over the goal drawn on the initial map,
今では道標無しでどこでもすぐに辿り着ける様になった。成長だ。
now, without signposts, I can reach anywhere immediately. That is growth.
そして今日、私は3枚目の地図へと進む。
And today, I advance to the third map.
たくさんやりたい事だらけでまだまだ手探りだけど、今の私はひとりじゃない。
There are so many things I want to do and I'm still feeling my way around, but the me of now is not alone.
たくさんの開拓者のみんながずっとそばにいてくれてたことを改めて強く感じてる。
I feel strongly once again that all my fellow pioneers have always been by my side.
新たな決意を持って、これからもみんなと一緒に私は歌い続ける。
With a new determination, I will continue to sing together with everyone from now on.
扉の向こうを繋いで 生まれたはずの世界は 思うよりずっと難しくて 夢がこぼれた
Connecting beyond the door, the world that should have been born was much harder than I thought, and dreams spilled over.
伝えたいことなんて いくつもあるわけないから
There's no way I have so many things I want to tell you,
儚く脆い僕の声は 擦れて揺れた
my fragile and frail voice rasped and quivered.
三度目の何とかだって 続ける意味を探して
Searching for a reason to keep going, even on the third try,
見たかった旅の先 これでいいと よかったと そう言えるまで
to the destination I wanted to see, until I can say "this is fine, I'm glad."
このまま終われば誰かの美談として消費されていくでしょうか？
If it ends like this, will I be consumed as someone else's heartwarming story?
ずっと後悔ばかり思い出す日々を 背負って笑う今だ
Carrying days of nothing but regret, this is me laughing right now.
そんな悲しい顔をしないで きっと間違ってないから
Don't make such a sad face, because I'm definitely not wrong.
間違いになんて絶対にしないよ
I will never let it be a mistake.
すれ違いの一つ二つだって 気にしないように過ごしてた
Trying not to mind one or two misunderstandings, I went about my days.
青さの宿ったこの体を愛してたから
Because I loved this body imbued with youthfulness.
何者にもなれなくて もがき続けた時間ごと
Embracing all the time I struggled without becoming anyone special,
肯定できるか分からない 分からないけど
can I affirm it? I don't know, I don't know, but—
辛ければ辛いほど 笑い話にもなるでしょう？
The more painful it is, the funnier the story will become, right?
君の声だって聴こえるから
Because I can hear your voice, too.
大丈夫だよ 大丈夫だよ 最高な日も 最悪な日も 音楽とともに刻んできた
It'll be all right. It'll be all right. The best days and the worst days alike, I've etched them into music.
これが生き様と呼べるなら 目的になんて無い
If this can be called a way of living, then there is no purpose.
僕は生きている
I am alive.
何度願い 何度滲み 何度怒り 何度嘘ついてしまったんだ
How many wishes, how many tears, how many angers, how many lies have I told?
こんなみすぼらしくて恥ずかしくて真面目過ぎる僕を 隠さずに晒すよ
Exposing my pathetic, embarrassing, too-earnest self without hiding it,
ずっと誰にも言えないこの気持ちを 吐き出してしまいたい
I want to spit out this feeling I could never tell anyone.
君を傷つけてしまうよ
It might hurt you.
初めて夢を描いたときから もう何年経った？
How many years have passed since I first dreamed?
気付いたらみんな居なくなっていた
Before I knew it, everyone was gone.
僕らは出会いと別れを繰り返していく
We keep repeating meetings and partings.
ただ時間が過ぎて 終わりが来る これでいい？後悔は？
Just as time passes and the end comes, is this okay? Any regrets?
あとは自分で決めるだけだ
The rest is up to me to decide.
綺麗でいびつな思い出を 歌にしよう
Let's turn our beautiful, distorted memories into a song.
何回でも そう何回でも 届けよう
No matter how many times, yes, no matter how many times, let's deliver it.
残酷な夢の世界で 誰かの歌が聴こえる
In this cruel dream world, I hear someone's song.
今日も音楽に救われて 僕は生きている
Saved by music again today, I am alive.
ということで、お届したのか、AZKiの新曲「エンドロールは終わらない」でした。
With that, the song I just delivered is AZKi's new song, "Endroll wa Owaranai."
え、こちらの曲は、瀬名快伸さんに書き下ろしていただきました。
Uh, this song was written down for us by Kaishin Sena.
え、今までのAZKiの思い出だったり、そして新しい一歩を踏み出すためのの曲となっています。
Uh, it's a song that encapsulates memories of AZKi up until now, as well as taking a new step forward.
どうでしたか？
How was it?
え、この曲には裏話があるので、また今度お話ししますね。
Uh, there's a backstory to this song, so I'll talk about it another time.
はい、ということで、皆さんお待たせいたしました！
Yes, with that, everyone, thank you for waiting!
ここで重大発表をしてくださーい！
Now, please make the major announcement!
ということで、重大発表の映像がございます。ご覧ください！
With that, we have the video for the major announcement. Please take a look!
重大発表
[Announcement]
「エンドロールは終わらない」7月1日24時より先行配信スタート
["Endroll wa Owaranai" Early digital release starting July 1st at 24:00]
2023.10.4 メジャーデビュー決定
[Major Debut Confirmed for October 4, 2023]
メジャーデビューEPリリース
[Major Debut EP Release]
AZKi、10月4日にビクターエンタテインメントよりメジャーデビューが決定いたしました！
AZKi will make her major debut from Victor Entertainment on October 4th!
はい、ということで重大発表はこちらのメジャーデビュー、そして、EPのリリースを10月4日にさせていただくことになりました！
Yes, so the major announcements are this major debut, and we will be releasing an EP on October 4th!
本日の8時から予約開始いたします。
Reservations start today at 8:00 PM.
そして、本日24時に先ほど歌った「エンドロールは終わらない」が配信開始！
And tonight at 24:00, "Endroll wa Owaranai," which I sang earlier, starts streaming!
詳細 は ツイート など を チェック し て ください !
Please check tweets and details for more information!
はい 、 と いう こと で 、 え 、 今日 こう いう 発表 を する こと が
Yes, so, being able to make this announcement today...
本当に 本当に 今日 ここ まで 応援 し て くださっ た 皆 さん が い た から だ と 思っ て い ます 。
I believe it's because of everyone who has supported me all the way here today.
え 、 ルート アルファ 、 え 、 ベータ を 飛び越え て 、 え 、 ルート ガンマ の 世界 に やっ て き まし た 。
I've leaped over Root Alpha and Root Beta, and arrived in the world of Root Gamma.
え 、 この ルート が 開け た の は 応援 し て くれ て 開拓 者 の みんな が い た から です 。
The reason this route opened up is because of all the pioneers who supported me.
え 、 アーティスト と し て 音楽 の 活動 も 精一杯 頑張っ て いく の で 、 これから も どうぞ よろしく お願い し ます !
As an artist, I'll continue to do my absolute best in my music activities, so I look forward to your continued support!
え 、 詳しく は あずき メジャー デビュー 特設 サイト を ご覧 ください !
For details, please check the AZKi major debut special site!
そして 、 最後 に 、 誕生日 と いえ ば まだ あれ が あれ を 発表 し て い ませ ん でし た ね 。
And finally, speaking of birthdays, there's still something we haven't announced yet, right?
と いう こと で 、 こちら ! あずき 生誕 グッズ 2023 と いう こと で 、
And so, here it is! AZKi Birthday Commemoration Goods 2023!
え 、 この 後 、 こちら も 20 時 に 発売 開始 に なり ます 。 と いう こと で 、 かけ足 に なり ます が 、 一つ ずつ 紹介 し て いき たい と 思い ます 。
These will go on sale at 20:00 tonight as well. So, I'll go through them quickly, one by one.
まず は こちら ! はい 、 B 2 タペストリー !
First is this! Yes, the B2 tapestry!
え 、 一緒 に ね 、 今回 の テーマ は 一緒 に 旅 を する と いう こと で 、 旅 を し て いる ところ を 書き下ろし て いただき まし た 。
The theme this time is traveling together, so they drew a brand new illustration of us traveling.
イラストレーター は 松 2 先生 ! え 、 今回 発売 する グッズ ね 、 こちら の あの キー ビジュアル な ん です けれど も 、 よく 見 とい て ください 。 はい 。
The illustrator is Matsuni-sensei! The key visual for the goods being released this time, please take a good look at it. Yes.
と いう こと で 、 あの 、 この 身 に つけ て いる グッズ も これ から 紹介 し ます 。
So, I'll also introduce the goods I'm wearing.
次 は こちら ! SNS 風 アクリル キーホルダー !
Next is this! SNS-style acrylic keychain!
と いう こと で 、 旅行 先 で 一緒 に あずき と 写真 を 撮れる グッズ に なっ て おり ます 。 いろんな 場所 で 一緒 に 写真 を 撮っ て ください !
This is a piece of merch where you can take pictures with AZKi together on your travels. Please take pictures together in various places!
え 、 イラスト は すず みしろ 先生 の 書き下ろし に なっ て おり ます 。
The illustration is newly drawn by Suzumishiro-sensei.
そして 、 こちら ! ミニ ドラム バッグ !
And, this! Mini drum bag!
と いう こと で キー ビジュアル の あずき と おそろい の ミニ ドラム バッグ です 。 ミニ だ けど 結構 容量 が ある の で 使い勝手 よし です 。
This is a matching mini drum bag with the AZKi in the key visual. It's mini, but it has plenty of capacity, so it's super convenient to use.
続き まし て 、 こちら ! キャップ ! こちら も キー ビジュアル の あずき が 身 に つけ て いる 、 え 、 おそろい の キャップ に なっ て い ます 。
Next, this! Cap! This is also a matching cap that AZKi is wearing in the key visual.
シンプル で 、 とっても ロゴ も 可愛い でしょ ? 普段 使い も できる デザイン に なっ て おり ます 。
It's simple, and the logo is super cute, right? It's designed for everyday use too.
え 、 ミニ ドラム バッグ と ね 、 ロゴ が 一緒 な の で 、 これ を 、 これ を かぶっ て 、 そして ミニ ドラム バッグ を 背負っ て 、 え 、 旅 に 出よう と いう こと で 、 そんな テーマ の グッズ に なっ て おり ます 。
The logo is the same as the mini drum bag, so the theme of this merch is wearing this cap, carrying the mini drum bag on your back, and setting off on a journey!
さらに 、 こちら ! 記念 ボイス ! え 、 きみ と あて の ない 旅 と いう こと で 、 旅 を テーマ に した シチュエーション ボイス に なっ て おり ます 。
Furthermore, this! Commemorative Voice! "An Aimless Journey with You", a situation voice themed around traveling.
そして 、 最後 に こちら ! え 、 誕生日 記念 フル セット ! 今 紹介 し た グッズ 4 種類 と 、 え 、 ボイス 1 種 、 そして 特典 で
And finally, this! Birthday Commemoration Full Set! The 4 types of goods just introduced, 1 type of voice, and as a bonus...
ポスト カード と ボイス が 付い て き ちゃい ます !
A postcard and voice come included!
で 、 前回 数量 限定 で 買え なかっ た 人 も い た みたい な ので 、 今回 は 全員 に なんと フル セット を 買う と 直筆 サイン を つけ ます ! つけ ます ! はい 。
It seemed like some people couldn't buy it last time due to limited quantities, so this time, if everyone buys the full set, I will include a handwritten signature! I will! Yes.
ええ と 、 最近 ね 、 あずき を 知っ て くれ た そこ の 開拓 者 の 君 ! はい 、 あずき が まごころ 込め て サイン を 書き ます の で 、 ぜひ ぜひ フル セット 手 に 入れ て ください !
Um, recently, you, the pioneer who got to know AZKi! Yes, AZKi will put her heart into signing them, so please, please get the full set!
はい 、 と いう こと で 、 めちゃくちゃ かけ足 に なり まし た が 、 本日 は あずき 生誕 ライブ 2023 に お越し いただき ありがとう ござい まし た !
Yes, so, it was extremely rushed, but thank you very much for attending the AZKi Birthday Live 2023 today!
ええ 、 本当 に 今 ここ に あずき が いる こと は 奇跡 な ん です ね 。 本当 に 奇跡 みたい な こと です 。
Um, it really is a miracle that AZKi is here right now. It's truly like a miracle.
え 、 この 瞬間 を 、 え 、 見守っ て くれ て 本当 に ありがとう ござい ます 。 これから も 一緒 に 世界 を 作っ て いこう ね 。 え 、 私 の 目的 地 は いつだって 、 君 と 一緒 に たどり着い た 場所 です 。
Thank you so much for watching over this moment. Let's keep creating the world together. My destination is always the place I reached together with you.
と いう こと で 、 あずき でし た ! みんな ありがとう ! また 会い ましょう ! なんと この 後 20 時 15 分 から アンコール ライブ が あり ます の で 、 メンバーシップ 開拓 者 組合 の 皆 さん は すぐ に お 会い し ましょう ! と いう こと で 、 あずき でし た ! ありがとう ござい まし た !
And with that, it was AZKi! Thank you everyone! See you again! Also, there will be an encore live starting from 20:15 just after this, so members of the Pioneer Guild, let's meet right away! So, it was AZKi! Thank you very much!
いつも道に迷ったときは
迷い込んだ日のことを思い出していたよ。
Whenever I got lost,
I would remember the day I wandered in.
今日7回目の誕生日を迎えることができたのも、君がいたから。
I was able to celebrate my 7th birthday today because you were there.
本当にありがとう。
これからも一緒に歩いていこうね。
Thank you so much.
Let's keep walking together from now on.
大好きだよ。
AZKi
2023.07.01
I love you.
AZKi
2023.07.01
いつも道に迷ったときは 助けられたこと忘れないでいたよ。
Whenever I lost my way, I never forgot how you helped me.
今日 7回目の誕生日を迎えることが できたのは、君がいたから。
The reason I can celebrate my 7th birthday today is because you were here.
本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much.
これからも一緒に歩いていこうね。 大好きだよ。
Let's keep walking together from now on, too. I love you.
AKI
2023.07.01